Women's movement collection (Andrea Lebowitz collector)
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
Women's movement collection (Andrea Lebowitz collector)
1967 - 1999
F-164
Q106660415
39 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
Lebowitz, Andrea
Andrea Pinto Lebowitz came to Simon Fraser University in 1965 as a charter faculty member in the Department of English. Lebowitz participated in a number of feminist activities including the Women's Caucus. She became the first coordinator of the Women's Studies program and transferred her appointment to the Women's Studies Department in 1997.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the collection is based on its subject matter and name of the collector.
Fonds contains material relating to Lebowitz's career at SFU and her participation in the Corrective Collective, a feminist writing group active in the 1970s. Fonds includes correspondence, minutes, proposals, publications, newspapers, invoices, receipts, a ledger, and other documents.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Lebowitz, Andrea; Corrective Collective; Women
Andrea Lebowitz donated the collection to the SFU Archives in 2001.
All accessions have been processed as of March 2006. No further accruals are expected.
Also see the inventories for Department of Women's Studies / SFU Archives (collector), F-62 and Frances Wasserlein fonds, F-162.
The files are open with no restrictions.
Series descriptions and file and item lists are available. Appendices contains autobiographical notes and Andrea Lebowitz's comments on the fonds and the Corrective Collective.
- Office files, 1967 - 1999; F-164-1; 9 cm of textual records
  published
  Series contains records relating to highlights of Andrea Lebowitz's career at SFU and the development of the Women's Studies Program. One file of reference material contains publications on abortion, daycare, working women, and women at the Canadian Broadcasting Company. Includes correspondence, minutes, proposals, publications, and other documents.
  - SFU Theatre Company, 1967; F-164-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
    Textual records
    Open
  - Works of Art committee, 1967; F-164-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - Reference material - women's issues, 1973 - 1977; F-164-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - Proposal for a Women's Studies program, 1974; F-164-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - Women's Studies Steering committee, 1975; F-164-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - Women's Studies program, 1979 - 1982; F-164-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - Women's Studies MA, 1981; F-164-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - 3M teaching fellowship, 1987; F-164-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - Maggie Benston Memorial Service, 1991; F-164-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - President's lecture - Andrea Lebowitz, 1999; F-164-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - Ruth Woodward Chair in Women's Studies, 1986; F-164-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
- Corrective Collective records, 1971 - 1977; F-164-2; 30 cm of textual records
  Series contains records made or received by the Corrective Collective during the course of writing, publishing and selling two books: She Named It Canada Because That's What It Was Called (Vancouver, 1971), and Never Done, Three Centuries of Women's Work in Canada (Vancouver, 1974). The former, a pictorial history of Canada, was originally produced as a handout for a conference of Vietnamese and North American women held in Vancouver. The latter was a history of non-aboriginal women in Canada. The file, "Published resource material" includes various feminist publications (such as the Saskatoon Women's Liberation Newsletter) and directories. The Collective used them to get ideas for publication formats and to prepare distribution lists. Series includes a copy of each publication, correspondence, memorandum of agreement, notes, receipts, a ledger and other documents.
  The copy of Never Done was donated to the SFU Archives by Honorée Newcombe for inclusion in these papers.
  Further information on the Corrective Collective provided by Andrea Lebowitz is available in the hard copy version of the finding aid maintained in the Archives Reading Room.
  - She Named It Canada - third revised edition, 1972; F-164-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - She Named It Canada - first edition, autographed, 1971; F-164-2-0-0-1.1 (Newspaper box 164-4)
  - She Named It Canada - second revised edition, 1971; F-164-2-0-0-1.2 (Newspaper box 164-4)
  - She Named It Canada - publication and grant history, 1972 - 1974; F-164-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - She Named It Canada - miscellaneous notes and correspondence, 1972 - 1974; F-164-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - She Named It Canada - sales to school districts, 1973; F-164-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 164-1)
  - Never done - correspondence, 1974 - 1976; F-164-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - Never done - single copy sales, 1974 - 1975; F-164-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - Never done - additional sales and royalties, 1976; F-164-2-0-0-6.1 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - Never done - paid bookstore receipts, 1974 - 1975; F-164-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - Never done - paid receipts, 1974 - 1975; F-164-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - She Named It Canada, Never Done - miscellaneous sales and financial records, 1975; F-164-2-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - Never done - ledger, expense records, 1974 - 1975; F-164-2-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - Never done / Three Centuries of Women's Work in Canada, 1974; F-164-2-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - Published resource material, 1974 - 1975; F-164-2-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 164-2)
  - Directory of Canadian Women's Groups 1/2, 1975; F-164-2-0-0-13 (Archival box - small 164-3)
  - Directory of Canadian Women's Groups 2/2, 1975; F-164-2-0-0-14 (Archival box - small 164-3)
  - Directory of Canadian Women's Groups, 1977; F-164-2-0-0-15 (Archival box - small 164-3)